Contact

wbloom@us.ibm.com

www.linkedin.com/in/bill-bloomfield (LinkedIn) ibm.com (Company)

Top Skills

Business Transformation Managed Services Governance

Certifications

IBM Virtual Collaborator

Enterprise Design Thinking Practitioner

Infrastructure Services Selling - Digital Transformation

IBM Selling Profession Certification - Level II

Insight Selling to the CxO

Bill Bloomfield

Accelerate IT transformation to improve business outcomes Middletown

Summary

Bill Bloomfield was named Industry Client Leader, US Industrial Market in March 2020, bringing 20+ years of successful sales and marketing leadership. In this role, Bill serves as the IBM point-person for his clients, aligning IBM's capabilities with their unique goals and objectives. Ultimately, he is responsible for the satisfaction his clients experience in their partnership with IBM. Accordingly, Bill invests in deep client relationships and follows the mantra "I win when my clients win".

Since joining IBM in September 1997, Bill has built a reputation for integrity, innovation, and consistency. He began his IBM career as a Marketing Specialist. His initial assignment was leading the development of the company's first global offering for IT managed services.

This position led to various sales and business development capacities between January 2000 – February 2020 where Bill succeeded by helping clients optimize and transform IT to accelerate and improve business outcomes. His clients have improved performance, accelerated digital transformation, and gained over \$500M in IT budget savings.

A Delaware resident since 1974, Bill received his Bachelor of Science degree in Financial Counseling and Planning from Purdue University and a Master of Business Administration degree from the Alfred Lerner College at the University of Delaware.

Bill serves as Vice President of the Westside Hunt Maintenance Corporation and is a LifeSaver donor with the Blood Bank of Delmarva. He is married and has two children. His family enjoys traveling and any opportunity to support local sports, arts, theater, and music.

Experience

IBM

23 years 3 months

Industry Client Leader - US Industrial Market March 2020 - Present (9 months)

Applying IBM's capabilities to achieve my clients unique goals and objectives

Strategic Services Executive

January 2000 - February 2020 (20 years 2 months)

Signed \$2.2B in global, multi-tower, annuity-based IT Managed Services

National Sales Leader

September 1998 - December 1999 (1 year 4 months)

Exceeded sales quota by 85%; reduced contract negotiations time by 75%

Marketing Specialist

September 1997 - August 1998 (1 year)

Developed IBM's first globally consistent IT managed services offering

BOULDEN, INC

Sales Team Leader

1989 - 1997 (8 years)

Conner, Marvel & Pierce Companies

Financial Planner

1988 - 1989 (1 year)

Education

University of Delaware - Lerner College of Business and Economics Master of Business Administration - MBA · (1995 - 1997)

Purdue University

Bachelor of Science - BS, Consumer and Family Sciences · (1983 - 1987)